let savollar9 = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "against",
        answer: "A. qarshi",
        options: [
            "A. qarshi",
            "B. uchun",
            "C. yonida",
            "D. ortida"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "beach",
        answer: "B. plyaj",
        options: [
            "A. tog'",
            "B. plyaj",
            "C. o'rmon",
            "D. ko'l"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "to damage",
        answer: "A. shikastlamoq",
        options: [
            "A. shikastlamoq",
            "B. tuzatmoq",
            "C. qurmoq",
            "D. e'tiborsiz qoldirmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "to discover",
        answer: "C. kashf qilmoq",
        options: [
            "A. yo'qotmoq",
            "B. vayron qilmoq",
            "C. kashf qilmoq",
            "D. yashirmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "emotion",
        answer: "D. his-tuyg'u",
        options: [
            "A. fikr",
            "B. harakat",
            "C. xotira",
            "D. his-tuyg'u"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "to fix",
        answer: "B. tuzatmoq",
        options: [
            "A. zarar yetkazmoq",
            "B. tuzatmoq",
            "C. kechiktirmoq",
            "D. e'tiborsiz qoldirmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: "frank",
        answer: "A. samimiy",
        options: [
            "A. samimiy",
            "B. muloyim",
            "C. tortinchoq",
            "D. yaxshi"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "to identify",
        answer: "C. aniqlamoq",
        options: [
            "A. yashirmoq",
            "B. yo'qotmoq",
            "C. aniqlamoq",
            "D. unutmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "island",
        answer: "B. orol",
        options: [
            "A. qit'a",
            "B. orol",
            "C. ko'l",
            "D. cho'l"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "ocean",
        answer: "D. okean",
        options: [
            "A. daryo",
            "B. ko'l",
            "C. sharshara",
            "D. okean"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "perhaps",
        answer: "A. balki",
        options: [
            "A. balki",
            "B. aniq",
            "C. hech qachon",
            "D. har doim"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "pleasant",
        answer: "C. yoqimli",
        options: [
            "A. yoqimsiz",
            "B. zerikarli",
            "C. yoqimli",
            "D. stressli"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "to prevent",
        answer: "A. to'sqinlik qilmoq",
        options: [
            "A. to'sqinlik qilmoq",
            "B. sabab bo'lmoq",
            "C. qo'llab-quvvatlamoq",
            "D. rag'batlantirmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "rock",
        answer: "B. tosh",
        options: [
            "A. qum",
            "B. tosh",
            "C. daraxt",
            "D. suv"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "to save",
        answer: "A. saqlamoq",
        options: [
            "A. saqlamoq",
            "B. vayron qilmoq",
            "C. yo'qotmoq",
            "D. sotmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "to step",
        answer: "D. qadam tashlamoq",
        options: [
            "A. yugurmoq",
            "B. sakramoq",
            "C. uchmoq",
            "D. qadam tashlamoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "still",
        answer: "B. hali ham",
        options: [
            "A. hech qachon",
            "B. hali ham",
            "C. to'satdan",
            "D. darhol"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "taste",
        answer: "A. ta'm",
        options: [
            "A. ta'm",
            "B. rang",
            "C. hid",
            "D. tovush"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "to throw",
        answer: "C. otmoq",
        options: [
            "A. ushlamoq",
            "B. ushlab turmoq",
            "C. otmoq",
            "D. ko'tarmoq"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "wave",
        answer: "D. to'lqin",
        options: [
            "A. shamol",
            "B. bo'ron",
            "C. chaqmoq",
            "D. to'lqin"
        ]
    }
];
